《勇敢者的游戏：宇宙历险》
喔
Oh, man.
对啦 就这样
That's it.
接得漂亮
Nice grab.
哦耶
Oh, yeah.
好了 丹尼 轮到你了
All right, Danny, your turn.
这么快？我的回合还没有结束呢
What? I didn't get my full turn.
得了吧 我数过了
You did. I counted.
25个回合 我们之间说好的
That was 25. That's what we said.
- 这不公平 - 这恰恰就是公平
- That's not fair. - It's exactly fair.
来吧 丹尼
Come on, Danny.
轮到你了 这轮结束后我得去工作一个小时
Time for your turn, then I gotta work for an hour.
要知道 爹地可不是只陪你一个人玩
You know, you're not the only one who gets a turn.
「只陪一个人玩」
"The only one who gets a turn."
孩子们
Guys.
好啦
All right.
你得全神贯注盯着球的来路
Keep your eye on the ball.
把握好接的时机 准备好了？
You got it this time. Ready?
好 接得挺好！只是我扔的太烂了 我的错
All right, that's a good try. It was a bad throw. It's a bad throw.
对不起咯我的错
Sorry. My bad.
好了 再来一次 这次你能接到的！
Okay. Here we go. You can do this.
我要传球了 准备好了？
Here we go. Ready?
准备好了！
Okay.
球高高飞向右边场地
A deep fly ball to the right field.
克莱门特补位策应 飞速回追接球
Clemente back, running on his horse real fast.
他能接到球吗？他能做到吗？
Can he get it? Can he get it?
噢 米尔顿·布拉德利做了个鱼跃翻身式的拦截
Oh, and Milton Bradley with his dive-and-roll catch.
- 「闪躲者」队胜利了 - 你真是个恶棍
- Dodgers win. - You're such a dick.
这有什么关系？这个拦截不精彩吗？
What? It was a great grab.
丹尼？
Danny?
丹尼 你不该用那样的词来形容你哥哥
Danny, you should not be using that kind of language with your brother.
可他就是那么坏
But it's true.
听着 宝贝 当我六岁大的时候…
Listen, kiddo, when I was 6 years old…
六岁 九个月
Six and three quarters.
当我在六岁九个月大的时候…
When I was 6 and three quarters…
接球对我来说是件很困难的事
catching was hard for me too.
喔 对沃尔特来说 那可轻松了
Well, it's not hard for Walter.
可沃尔特现在已经10岁了
Well, Walter's 10.
那又如何 反正他做什么都比我强
So? He's still better than me at everything.
哪里 他钢琴就没你弹得好
No way. He's not better than you at piano.
可我又不喜欢钢琴…
I hate that stupid thing.
总有一天 你甚至会感谢我送给了你那架钢琴
Someday you're gonna be really happy I got you that piano.
你会有机会在聚会上演奏 而有个美丽的女孩也为你所吸引…
You'll be at a party, there'll be a pretty girl…
这就是你和妈妈的故事？
Like you and Mom?
听着 丹尼…
Look, Danny…
你和沃尔特可不同
you and Walter are different people.
每个人各有自己拿手好戏 他有他的强项
He's good at some things, you're good at other things.
你也有你的擅长
That's how people are.
他做什么都赢我
He beats me at everything.
听我说 了解这点很重要
Listen to me, this is important.
你是个很特别的孩子
You're a very special kid.
人们想不出办法来解释事实时 总用这样的话来推脱
That's what people say when they can't think of anything.
记得你总是自己编个游戏…
You know how you always make up games…
并扮演其中的角色吗？
and pretend to be characters?
那恰恰说明你拥有 与众不同的想象力
You have an incredible imagination.
不可思议的想象力 丰富而不凡！
Amazing imagination. A whole universe of an imagination.
我是靠想象力工作的人 所以我的评价就特别有价值
And I use my imagination for a living, so I know what I'm talking about.
- 我的想象力比沃尔特好吗？- 什么？
- Is it better than Walter's? - What?
我的想象力比沃尔特好吗？
Is my imagination better than Walter's?
你比沃尔特更与众不同
You're different than Walter.
- 别做这么危险的举动 - 玩儿传接球吗？
- Don't do that. - You wanna play catch?
- 不是刚玩过吗？- 不 用橄榄球来玩儿
- We just played catch. - No, football catch.
我说过 我得工作上一小时
I have to work for an hour.
- 可今天是周六！- 那又怎么样呢
- But it's Saturday. - Tell me about it.
- 你总是说要工作 - 说得好
- All you ever do is work. - Nice try.
- 偏心！- 你好
- This is so unfair. - Hello.
比尔 我很抱歉
Bill, I am so sorry.
我两分钟内就给你回电 如何？
I'll call you back in two minutes. Is that okay?
谢了
Thanks.
今天下午我得参加一个相当重要的会议
I have an important meeting this afternoon.
- 我得… 好好做些准备 - 你要出门吗？
- I've… I really have to be ready for it. - You're going out?
没错 我得出门去 有一个会议需要出席
Yes, I'm going out. Well, I'm going to a meeting.
反正 你们就要到妈妈家去了
You're gonna be at Mom's house.
她在3点左右就会来接你们
She's coming to get you at 3.
不是明天才去妈妈那儿吗？
We go to Mom's house tomorrow.
- 不 是今天 - 这周你得照看我们4天！
- No, today. - This is a four-day Dad week.
「3天爹地」周 上周「4天妈咪」周…
Three-day Dad week. Four-day last week…
下周我得带你们4天 而这周我带你们3天就够了
four-day next week, three-day this week.
这周就是「4天妈咪周」
Four-day Mom week this week.
太不公平啦！
But that's not fair.
- 对谁不公平？- 对每个人都是
- To whom? - To anyone.
我得工作！
I have to work.
如果没丹尼捣乱的话 我们本就能好好享受这几天
We'd have all the time if Danny wasn't around.
喔 丹尼确实无处不在
Well, Danny is around.
好吧 就陪我最后扔5个！
All right, five throws.
该怎么办呢 我想想 我得工作！
How do I put this? Let me think. I have to work.
爹地 现在可以陪我玩「毁灭兄弟」了
Dad, I'm ready to play "Smash Bros."
你答应和他玩「毁灭兄弟」？
You told him you'd play "Smash Bros"?
没有！我没答应陪他玩什么「毁灭兄弟」
No, I didn't tell him I was gonna play "Smash Bros."
你要和沃尔特玩传接球？
You're playing catch with Walter?
如果你没一直烦我们 他当然会
He might if you weren't around.
你对我太坏了 每个人都不想我过得开心
You're so mean. Everybody wants to ruin my life.
你总不遵守诺言
You never keep your promises.
你们的父亲只有一个 好不好！
There's only one of me, okay?
我可不喜欢这样的情形 你们总是这样争吵…
I don't like this situation either, it sucks, is what it does…
但这是我所能做的最大的努力了
but this is the best I could come up with.
你们可否离我远点儿 给我点留自己的空间？
So climb off my back and give me about two inches of space, will you?
你们还会一起经历很多 孩子们
There are some days, boys,
在你们成长的路上
when you gotta grow up all at once.
我希望经过今天发生的事你们 学得再懂事点
I need today to be one of those days.
玩儿飞行棋吗？
Wanna play Chutes and Ladders?
不 你会耍赖的
No, you'll cheat.
那玩脑力挑战赛怎么样？
Stratego?
不 你玩棋盘游戏总是作弊
No, you cheat at board games.
可在脑力挑战赛中没法作弊嘛
But you can't even cheat at Stratego.
少来这套 反正你总是有办法耍赖
Trust me, you'll find a way.
嘿 很抱歉
Hey. Sorry about that.
喔 不 不没什么
Oh, no, no, it's fine.
我想3：30准能完成 那时我去见他
I'm not meeting him till 3:30, I can finish by then.
沃尔特 看看我找到了什么
Walter, look what I found.
这是我的东西 把它们放回原位去
Those belong to me. Put them back.
可我从没见你玩过
But you never play with them.
那又如何 它们还是我的
So? They're still mine.
我都不记得你从何时开始 对我这么不客气了！
When did you get so mean?
我可没故意针对你 丹尼
I'm not mean, Danny.
你要知道 我四年级了 已经有女朋友了
I'm in fourth grade, I have a girlfriend.
记得爹地说的：我们得学着快点长大 别再那么幼稚？
You know how Dad said we have to grow up?
喔 我们得照他说的做
Well, this is what it looks like.
我们玩「军官」游戏好吗？
Can we please play "Army Men"?
报告情况
Copy that.
中士 有一架直升机起火了
Sergeant, there is a helicopter on fire.
我们得去处理一下
Let's get it.
制图和实体模型大小完全吻合
The drawings all match the foam mockup.
- 还给我！- 就让我拿着嘛
- Get back here. - Let me hold it.
- 对 是红色 - 给我！
- Yes, red. - Give me.
酸果蔓红 对 就是他们选的那颜色
Cranberry, right. It's whatever color they picked.
当初我有记下来
I worked from the chits.
我能过会再给您挂过去吗？家里有点事得处理一下
Can I call you back one more time? It's a small domestic emergency here.
我… 我… 知道 我知道
I… I… I know. I know.
- 爹地 - 没问题 好的 谢了
- Dad. - It's not a problem. Okay, thanks.
- 看看他做的好事 - 我刚才可是在接电话！
- Look what he did. - I was on the phone.
- 这只是个意外 - 你就是这么不懂事
- It was an accident. - You're such a baby.
- 我不是！- 你要弄坏我所有的东西才高兴？
- I'm not a baby. - You break all my stuff.
- 你连个球都接不住… - 够了
- You can't catch a ball… - That's enough.
- 没人喜欢你在旁边烦！- 你给我闭嘴！
- and nobody wants you around. - You shut up!
我错了 对不起 对不起
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
对不起 对不起
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
我得去办公室一下 10分钟就回来
It's 10 minutes to the office.
我得再赶份新的草图出来 等我回来喔
I have to run off another copy. I'll be back.
你就让我俩自个儿 呆在这间毛骨悚然的屋子里？
You're gonna leave us alone in this creepy old house?
- 这没什么好害怕的 就是旧了点 - 妈妈才不会这样
- It's not creepy, it's old. - I like Mom's better.
喔 没错反正现在也轮她了
Well, so did she, and now it's hers.
听着 这是间十分不一般的房子
Look, this is a very special house.
我努力工作来整修它的原因是
The reason I'm working to fix it up is.
我想让这儿成为我们温暖的家
I wanna make a home for us here.
我知道这里不像妈妈的屋子那么好
Now, I know it's not Mom's house,
而确实这房子已经有些破旧了…
and I know it's a little creaky…
但是 给它点时间 它会让你们有家的感觉！
but give it some time, it's gonna grow on you.
喔 我可不想孤零零地呆这儿
Well, I don't wanna stay here alone.
喔 你们不会觉得孤单的 我去叫醒丽莎来陪你们
Well, you're not gonna be alone. I'm going to wake up Lisa.
- 不 别叫醒丽莎！- 什么？你疯了吗？
- No, don't wake up Lisa. - What, are you crazy?
她还在睡觉呢 就让她睡吧！
She's sleeping. Let her sleep.
甜心
Honey.
丽莎 甜心
Lisa. Honey.
起来吧
Get up.
我得出去一下 你得帮忙照顾一下你最喜爱的那俩个小家伙
I need to go out. I need you to look after your two favorite people.
起来吧
Come on.
不行嘛 我晚上有约会呢！
I can't. I have a date tonight.
几点的？
What time?
我们好象是约八点
We're hooking up at, like, 8.
- 现在才两点 - 那又怎样？
- It's 2. - So?
离你的约会还有六个小时呢
So that's six hours from now.
你想怎么样嘛？
What's your point?
我要你好好照看那俩活宝
I need you to look after the boys.
还有 这让我很不舒服的是你用「上钩」来形容你的约会
By the way, it makes me uncomfortable when you say "hooking up."
又怎么了？那又不意味着会发生什么事
Why? It's not like it means anything.
- 希望不会 - 不会啦 只是种说法罢了
- Hope it doesn't. - It doesn't. It's just an expression.
- 希望如此 - 当然啦！天那
- Hope it is. - It is. God.
我们真不该租《芳龄十三》来看！
We never should have rented Thirteen.
盯着点他们 别让他们把房子拆了
Keep your eye on them. Make sure they don't burn down the house.
- 听到了么？- 我又没聋
- Okay? - I'm not deaf.
- 我又没聋 - 什么？
- I'm not deaf. - What?
爹地！好了 我知道了！
Dad, okay.
十五分钟之内我就起来 行行好把门关上吧
Fifteen minutes, just close the door.
谢了
Thank you.
对是的
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I am.
好的先等等
Yeah, hold on.
嘿！
Hey!
爹地说过不让玩电视游戏！
Dad said no video games.
他没有
He did not.
好吧
Fine.
是长颈鹿宝宝
It's a giraffe.
- 现在是「体育中心」栏目时间 - 嘿
- This is SportsCenter. - Hey.
我也看过
I was watching that.
是奥克兰 是波士顿 那是曼尼·拉米雷兹
It is Oakland. It is Boston. It is Manny Ramirez.
- 我们不看超级海绵历险记吗？- 不
- Can't we watch SpongeBob? - No.
- 你以前不是喜欢吗？- 过去是过去
- You used to like it. - Times change.
嗒嗒沙拉酱
Tartar sauce.
我饿了
I'm hungry.
你想让我做什么？
So, what do you want me to do about it?
给我做奶酪通心面吧？
Make me macaroni and cheese?
我不会做
I don't know how.
我饿 那你会做什么咯？
I'm hungry. What do you know how to make?
水
Water.
两分全垒打！不可思议！
Two-run shot. Are you kidding me?
下个击球手 詹森 瓦里台克
Next batter, Jason Varitek.
球被击到空中 径直飞向右场尽头
In the air to deep right field. Down the line, towards the pole.
- 我们玩传接球好不？- 不要
- How about if you and me play catch? - No.
第一个全垒打跑垒的人…
The first guy to give up walk-off home runs…
自1998年至今
on consecutive days since 1998.
波士顿以6：5胜出
Bo Sox win it 6 to 5.
历史将会记得这一刻…
History-making moment for…
你死定了！
You're dead!
对不起 对不起 对不起
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
丹尼？
Danny?
你在哪儿？
Where are you?
丹尼？
Danny?
你在哪儿 丹尼？
Where are you, Danny?
丹尼？
Danny?
你在哪儿？
Where are you?
- 找到你了 - 我说了对不起
- There you are. - I said I was sorry.
别不！
Don't. No.
- 别这样 这不好玩 - 在爹地回来前 你就呆这儿吧
- Don't do that, it's not funny. - You'll be safe here till Dad gets back.
因为爹地觉得我比你聪明 所以你嫉妒了！
You're just jealous because Dad thinks I'm smarter than you.
我随便说说的
I didn't mean that.
沃尔特 不 拉我上来 别！
Walter. No. Pull me up. Don't.
这有什么关系 丹尼？
What's the matter, Danny?
我看这么大了 应该不怕地下室了吧？
Not still scared of the basement, are you?
沃尔特！不 沃尔特！
Walter! No, Walter!
这不好玩儿 不！
It's not funny! No!
拉我上去！沃尔特！
Pull me up! Walter!
3岁小孩才怕地下室！
Three-year-olds are scared of basements.
你太坏了！
You're really mean.
爹地说了别在那儿玩
Dad said not to play in there.
看看我在地下室找到了什么！
Look what I found in the basement.
无聊的老游戏
Looks dumb and old.
我喜欢！
I like it.
当然你会喜欢 这就是为小孩子准备的
Yeah, you would, it's for babies.
沃尔特 这游戏棒极了 过来看看
Walter, this is so cool. Check this out.
什么是Zathura？
What's Zathura?
- 和我一起玩吗？- 不
- Will you play with me? - No.
- 我不会耍赖皮的 - 喔 你会的
- I won't cheat. - Yeah, you will.
- 跳出了张卡片！- 不错
- A card came out. - Fascinating.
帮我读一下
Read this for me.
「流星雨降临 请回避」
"Meteor shower. Take evasive action."
什么叫快回避？
What's evasive action?
就是让你躲着点儿
It's when you get out of the way.
我要躲着点什么？
What exactly am I supposed to get out of the way of, exactly?
不知道 它就写着：「请回…」
I have no idea. All it says is "Take evasive a…"
奶奶啊！
Grandma.
流星雨！
It's meteors!
快躲好！
Take erasive action!
快闪！
丹尼 躲这儿来
Danny, in here.
丹尼 快 这里安全
Danny, hurry up. It's safe.
丹尼 来啊 快！
Danny, come on. Hurry.
Danny, come on, hurry up.
快 快 来 进来
Hurry, hurry, hurry. Come on. Get in, get in.
这里是「体育中心」栏目
This is SportsCenter.
谢林将不再与续约…
Schilling deals no love…
我觉得我们不该把那游戏再玩下去了
I don't think we should play that game anymore.
真奇怪
That's weird.
只有客厅被袭击了
It only hit the living room.
喔 太空！
Wow, outer space.
不 大概只是晚上到了
No, that's just nighttime.
我不知道 我总觉得从没看得这么清楚
I don't know, Walter. Night never looked so close before.
等等
Wait.
沃尔特 快来看！
Walter, check this out.
- 快告诉她 - 你说吧
- Tell her. - You tell her.
你说的话 她或许不会气得发疯
You should, she won't freak out as much.
我们或许不该到她房里来
We shouldn't really even be in here.
小子 我们呆在太空！现在你还管那么多？
Dude, we're in outer space. It doesn't matter.
那你叫醒她
Then you wake her.
我叫就我叫
Fine.
丽莎
Lisa.
丽莎 丽莎…
Lisa. Lisa…
- 离我远点儿 - 丽莎你得起来看看
- Go away. - Lisa, you gotta get up.
记得进我房间 你们得守什么规矩？
What's the rule about being in my room?
除非有紧急情况 否则 我们不能擅自进来
We're not allowed in unless it's an emergency.
那么 有什么紧急情况？
And what's the emergency?
刚下了场流星雨 好多东西都被砸坏了
There was a meteor shower and everything got wrecked.
- 我们回不了地球了 - 够了 闭嘴！
- We can't get back to Earth. - Okay, shut up!
- 你看 - 就是
- Just look. - Yeah.
- 噢 不 - 我们该怎么办？
- Oh, no. - What do we do?
天已经黑了？我要迟到了！
It's already dark? I'm gonna be so late.
- 不是天黑了！- 我们是被困在太空里了！
- It's not dark. - We're in outer space.
我都看见土星了
I saw Saturn outside.
丽莎 开门啊！
Lisa, open up.
闭上你们的嘴 听着！
Shut up and listen to me.
爹地让我在他回家前好好看着你们
Dad put me in charge until he got home.
这意味着 你们得事事都听我的！
Which means you guys need to do what I say.
帮个忙吧 都给我下楼呆着 别让我看到你们
Do me a favor. Go downstairs and stay out of my face.
但是 这是紧急情况
But it's an emergency.
- 房子有着火吗？- 没有
- Is the house on fire? - No.
- 有人伤着了？- 也没有 不过…
- Is anyone hurt? - No, but…
- 那就快离我远点儿 - 丽莎 求你了
- Then leave. - Lisa, please.
我们真的很害怕 你能帮我们看看这是什么鬼玩意儿吗？
We're really scared. Can you just watch what this game does?
如果这是你们捉弄人的无聊把戏 你们俩就死定了
If this is some weird joke you guys are trying to pull, you're dead.
不 这不是什么把戏
No, it's not a joke.
这儿 看这个
Here, watch this. Watch this. Here.
- 好了 先拧钥匙 - 好吧
- Okay. So wind the key. - All right.
- 那么我现在开始拧钥匙 - 好 你看
- So now I'm winding the key. - Yeah, see?
- 然后按这个键 - 就这样按？
- And then push the button. - So I push it?
- 对 - 按这个键
- Yeah. - Pushing the button.
接着数字就开始变化 停下时会显示个数字 比如说9
Then the number winds, and whatever the number is, like nine.
然后你的飞船… 蓝色的那艘…
Then your ship… The blue ship…
红色的是我的 我转到了五
because the red ship is mine, and I got a five.
然后它就走到第九格 就要发生了
So then it goes to nine, which would be that thing.
- 对 - 然后就会有张卡片跑出来
- All right. - Then the card's gonna pop out.
- 卡片 - 卡片
- The card. - The card.
- 出来了！- 卡片！
- The card! - The card!
- 就是这卡 - 可怕的事要发生了
- The card. - Here's the scary part.
「您被提升为船长
"You're promoted to a starship captain.
作为奖励 可向前移动两步「
Move ahead two spaces."
很有趣
Fascinating.
- 丽莎 不 不！丽莎！- 不 等等 丽莎！
- Lisa, no, no! Lisa! - No, wait, Lisa!
等等 那不算 该我走了 轮我了 好 看着
Wait, that one didn't count. Let me go. Let me go. Here. Okay.
卡住了？！
It's stuck.
或许我们该轮流来
Maybe we have to take turns.
看到了？该我了呢
See? It was my turn.
- 四！- 也 四步！
- Four. - Yeah, four.
卡
Card.
船员进入冷冻睡眠室5回合
Shipmate enters cryonic sleep chamber for 5 turns.
这到底什么意思？
What the heck does that mean?
丽莎？
Lisa?
「冷冻」是冰冻的意思吗？
Does "cryonic" mean ice?
丽莎
Lisa.
帮帮我
Help.
是我杀了她！
I killed her.
你没有害她
You didn't kill her.
她只是被冻住了 有点像冬眠
She's frozen in cryonic sleep.
我得帮她把外层的冰给化了
I gotta melt her.
你疯了？！
Are you crazy?
我们不能就让她保持这样的状态
We can't just leave her here like this.
或许读读游戏说明对我们会有帮助
Maybe we should read the instructions.
「Zathura注意了 太空冒险者们
"Zathura. Attention, space adventurers.
Zathura等待着你们的到来
Zathura awaits.
航行中会遇到的无法预料的危险
Do you have what it takes to navigate the galaxy?
此游戏不适合心脏脆弱者加入
It's not for the faint of heart.
一旦开始了冒险…
For once you embark upon your journey…
除非到达Zathura 否则就回不了头
there's no turning back until Zathura's reached.
在游戏结束后一切才会恢复正常
Pieces reset at the end of each game.
适合各年龄层的各种冒险者 百玩不厌「
Play again and again for different adventures."
就这些 看来我们得继续玩下去
That's it. We gotta keep playing.
我不想再碰那玩意儿了
I'm not playing that thing.
不 我们得继续！上面说只有我们胜利了 才能回去
Yes, we are. It says we go home if we win.
这… 上面没这样写着啊
It… It didn't say that.
写着呢 「在游戏结束后一切才会恢复正常 」
Yes, it did."Pieces reset at the end of each game."
那意味着 游戏一结束 我们就能回家了
That means we go home when we're finished.
在我看来 玩这游戏 没发生过什么好事儿
All I know is that when we play this game, bad things happen.
而对我来说 每按一次键 我就能多走几步
All I know is that when I played, I got promoted.
尽快走到终点 我们就能回家了
So I'm gonna win this and get us home.
- 等等 我们能停下… - 别耍孩子气
- Wait, can we stop… - Don't be a baby.
我不是个孩子了！
I'm not a baby.
你看 8步了 已经走到地图的一半了
Look, eight, I'm halfway there.
你的机器人有缺陷
Your robor is defectived.
那什么意思？
What does that mean?
它说我的机器人出故障了
Means my robot's broken.
可你压根儿就没机器人啊
But you don't even have a robot.
紧急情况
Emergency.
那就是你的机器人？
That's your robot?
- 至少我有个！- 喔 它能做什么？
- At least I got one. - Well, what does it do?
任何我想要它做的事！给我弄盒果汁来 快
Anything I want. Get me a juice box, beyotch.
- 别那么做！- 你管得着么？那是我的机器人
- Don't do that. - Why not? It's my robot.
- 你会让他发狂的 - 它不就3英尺高嘛
- You might make it mad. - It's 3 inches tall.
我能把它一脚踢出房间 那是我的机器人 卡片都写着呢
I'll punt it across the room. My robot, the card says.
我又没说那不是你的机器人 你别这么神经质好不好？
I never said it wasn't your robot. You don't have to be such a jerk.
小子 你根本就是嫉妒我有个机器人！
Dude, you're just jealous I have a robot and you don't.
- 你凭什么说我… - 紧急情况
- Why would I want… - Emergency.
紧急情况
Emergency.
发现外来生物
Alien life form.
必须消灭
Must destroy.
沃尔特 我想它是在说你呢
Walter, I think he's talking about you.
发现外来生物
Alien life form.
必须消灭
Must destroy.
丹尼 快继续你的回合
Danny, take your turn.
- 钥匙不见了 - 快找啊！
- There's no key. - Find it.
快 快 速度！
Take it, take it. Come on, hurry.
快继续啊！
Take your turn!
你刚才为什么不走？我差点被弄死了
Why didn't you go? I could have been killed.
我害怕极了 不过还好 反正它现在走没影了
I was scared. But it's okay, he's gone, isn't he?
丹尼 快继续你的回合
Danny, take your turn.
- 丹尼 把卡给我 - 飞船还在走呢
- Danny, give me the card. - It's still moving.
快 丹尼
Hurry up, Danny.
卡出来了！
The card.
卡上写着什么？
What did the card say?
你太靠近tsouris-3 进入重力场
You pass too close to tsouris-3. Enter gravity field.
丹尼！
Danny!
沃尔特！
Walter!
怎么了？
What?
- 发生了什么？- 是丽莎
- What happened? - It's Lisa.
她没事吧？
Is she okay?
沃尔特 你觉得呢？
Walter, do you think she's okay?
我想是的 她还是老样子
I guess. She's still in one piece.
机器人怎么样了？
What happened to the robot?
你要做什么？
What are you doing?
我想那家伙已经玩完了
I think it's dead.
别去
Get up here.
你觉得那扇门能关得住它吗？
Do you think the door will hold the robot?
不
No.
好吧
Great.
是啊 一旦它自我修复完毕 我们就得被它修理了！
Yeah, once he fixes himself, we're screwed.
它能自我修复？
He's fixing himself?
我怎么知道？
How should I know?
看来没事
Looks about right.
真没事？
You think she's okay?
我可不想她醒来时 在这被她逮个正着了
I don't wanna be here when she wakes up.
你去哪儿？
Where are you going?
继续我的回合
Taking my turn.
你疯了吗？我们已经弄得一团糟了！
Are you crazy? That thing's messed up.
「您被提升为舰队司令 请向前移动四步 」
"You're promoted to fleet admiral. Move ahead four spaces."
- 好了 轮到你了 - 我才不玩呢
- Okay, your turn. - I'm not playing.
- 你在做什么？- 奶酪通心粉
- What are you doing? - Making mac and cheese.
这儿没水 呆瓜 我们现在呆太空里呢
There's no water, dummy, we're in outer space.
你自己做？
Why are you doing that?
我饿了 而我知道你也不愿意照顾我
Because I'm hungry and I know you're not gonna take care of me.
别费心了 根本就没煤气
Don't bother, the gas won't work.
还有啥好建议吗？
Any more advice?
你得开大点儿火
You've gotta turn it up more.
和我谈好吗？
Can we at least talk about this?
没什么好谈的 反正我不会继续玩下去
There's nothing to talk about, I'm not going.
丹尼 我只想回地球 可没有你 我没法继续
Danny, I just wanna go home, and I can't unless you play.
你不想回去吗？
Don't you wanna get home?
回家有什么好的？
What's so great about home, anyway?
你什么意思？每件事本来都很完美 直到你出现
What do you mean? Everything was great until you came along.
你看？瞧瞧你对我的态度 像是所有的事都是我造成的
See? You treat me like everything's my fault.
是你先开始了这个游戏！
You're the one who pushed the button in the first place.
我只想和你一起玩游戏 沃尔特
I just wanted to play a game with you, Walter.
好吧 那你想怎么样？
Fine, what do you want?
我想要你不再对我那么刻薄 不再对我不理不睬…
I want you not to be mean to me, not ignore me…
还有 我希望你能像亲兄弟一样地对待我
and I want you to treat me like your brother.
- 好吧 - 那我们就原谅彼此了？
- Fine. - Do we have an understanding?
对
Yeah.
这不是容易吗？
Wasn't that easy?
六
Six.
涡刚人来访
You are visited by Zogrons.
什么是涡刚人？
What's a Zorgon?
我看应该不是什么坏事 或许只是些造访者
I don't think it's bad. Just visitors.
涡刚人！
Zorgons!
或许他们挺友好的
Maybe they're friendly.
看来不像！
They're not friendly!
对了 壁炉快躲到壁炉里去！
The fireplace. Hide in the fireplace.
快闪！
Run!
告诉过你我不想走的 都怪你！
Told you I didn't wanna go. You're the one who made me spin.
可我们没有其他选择
There's nothing else we could do.
- 还玩？- 有更好的主意吗？
- Are you crazy? - Got any better ideas?
「程序重组」？这什么意思？
"Reprogram"? What the heck does that mean?
你问我我问谁？！
How am I supposed to know?
程序重组！
Reprogram!
没用！
It didn't work.
说不定过会就能用上了
We'll figure it out later.
继续
Go.
- 不 - 继续啊
- No. - Go.
- 不！- 给我继续！
- No! - Go!
「在直立的阿斯特罗草皮上休息 」
"Rest on standing AstroTurf."
- 什么？- 在直立的阿斯特罗草皮上休息
- What? - Rest on standing AstroTurf.
- 给我看看 - 不 我念得没错儿
- Let me read it. - No, I know how to read.
- 我念得没错儿 - 给我看看 上帝
- I know how to read. - Let me read it. God.
拯救落难宇航员
Rescue Stranded astronaut.
落难的宇航员？
What stranded astronaut?
我想或许有什么宇航员遇到点麻烦或者…
I guess there's gonna be some stranded astronaut or some…
你锁门了吗？
Did you lock the door?
不知道
I don't know.
你俩谁把我骗来的？
Which one of you spun me?
- 哪位？- 他
- Who was it? - Him.
别这么快就把你兄弟出卖了 小东西
Don't be so quick to sell out your brother, kid.
他可是你唯一的同伴
He's all you got.
看来你们被涡刚人欺负得够呛
Looks like you got a pretty serious Zorgon problem.
是啊 我们该怎么办？
Yeah, what do we do?
- 藏起来 - 藏着？
- Hide. - Hide?
可它们会把整间房子给毁了的
They'll just explode the whole house.
我们得把房子藏起来
We're gonna hide the house.
切断所有电气用品的电源
Turn off all the lights and electrical appliances.
- 我？- 对 就是你 快去
- Me? - Yes, you. Go. Do it.
好
Okay.
你 过来 把炉子上的火关了！
You. Come on, kill that flame on the stove.
好的
Okay.
烧瓦斯那很可能是 它们被引来的最直接原因
Burning gas. That's probably what brought them in the first place.
好啦 现在去把高炉的标灯给灭了
Okay. Now get the pilot light on the furnace.
什么是标灯？
What's a pilot light?
在地下室 加热器下还燃烧着的那微弱火苗
In the basement. Little blue flame under the big heater.
像吹灭蜡烛一样 这样
Blow it out like a candle. Like this:
那家伙要把爹地的沙发给毁了
Walter, the astronaut guy is wrecking Dad's couch.
快
Come on.
那是爹地休息的沙发
That's Dad's nap couch.
你们不过来帮帮我把它弄出去？
You wanna help me get this out of here?
攻击它吧
Hit it.
- 怎么了？- 快
- What's happening? - Come on.
发现它啊
Take it.
跟它去
Follow it.
这就对了
There you go.
搞定了
That's it.
涡刚人
Zorgons.
是一种巨大而丑陋的蜥蜴
They're big, gnarly lizards.
它们是冷血的肉食者
Cold-blooded heatseekers.
即使是一点火星的温度 都会把它们成群地引来！
And the tiniest spark of warmth will bring them in like moths.
它们在星际中漂浮…
Flying all around the galaxy…
搜寻能拿来生火的东西
looking for anything they could find to burn up.
他们为什么不在自己的星球上找燃料？
Why don't they just burn up their own planet?
喔 他们确实有这样做
Oh, they already did.
可这还不是最糟糕的
That's not even the worst of it.
最令人害怕的 在于它们那填不满的贪婪欲望
The real problem is their ravenous appetite.
它们总是在找吃的
They never stop eating.
它们吃什么？
What do they eat?
- 肉 - 真有品位
- Meat. - That's good.
小子 你就是肉做的
Dude, you're meat.
这也是为了让涡刚人不再找上门来？
Are you doing this to keep Zorgons away?
不
Nope.
15年来我已经吃够了液体食物
I'm doing this because I've been eating paste out of a tube for 15 years.
- 真衰 - 怎么了？
- This totally sucks. - Why?
他要把我们的食物给吃光了！
He's eating all our food.
那又如何？卢皮已经去买东西了
So? Lupe just went shopping.
你知道我们还要在这里呆多久吗？
How long do you think we're gonna be out here?
有可能还得几个星期 那么你想
It could be weeks. Then what?
我不知道
I don't know.
还有这里的氧气？他呆这儿把氧气给吸个精光了 我们怎么办？
What about air? How long is it gonna last before he breathes it all up?
- 我想 - 我得和他谈谈
- I guess. - I'm gonna say something.
别 等等 沃尔特 沃尔特
No, wait. Walter. Walter.
伙计 这可是我们的食物
Dude, that's our food.
我知道 我看你们得勒紧裤腰带了
Yep. And you're running low on supplies.
对 我知道 几乎都到你肚子里去了
Yeah, I know. You're eating it all.
喔 可我好象记得卡片上写着：「救援落难的宇航员」
Well, as I recall, the card said, "Rescue stranded astronaut."
而我也确实帮了你俩大忙…
Looks to me like I'm the only one that's doing any rescuing…
那么 我可不认为 就吃你们几块三明治有多过分
so I don't think a couple Dagwood sandwiches is too much to ask for.
饿鬼 东西都要被你吃光了！
Dog, you're eating it all.
我穿过一个时间隧道才到这里
I passed through a time sphincter to get here.
知道那有多费力吗？
You realize how difficult that is?
不就是时间隧道么？
What's a time sphincter?
喔 可不像你们想的 那像一个虫洞 就这么大
A wormhole, about yay big:
你去那儿挤挤试试…
You squeeze through there…
没饿得能吞下条鲨鱼 我就不信你能钻过去
and tell me you're not hungry enough to eat a carpet shark.
看来你似乎还有挺多路要赶
Sounds like you got a long trip ahead of you.
喔你赶我走？
Oh, you telling me to leave?
喔 嗯至少你可以等吃完了再
Well, I mean, once you get finished eating, yeah.
喔 我不想让你失望 但我走不走不是你说了算的
Oh, I hate to break it to you, but that's not your call.
他把我找来的 所以得由他决定
He spun me, so it's up to him.
喔 我可是舰队司令 我命令你立刻离开！
Well, I'm fleet admiral, and I'm telling you to hit the road.
噢 抱歉 长官 我不… 不知道您是舰队司令
I apologize, sir. I didn't… I didn't realize you were a fleet admiral.
事实上 我…
In fact, I…
我也是舰队司令！
I'm a fleet admiral too.
你以为卡片说什么就是什么？傻瓜！
It's just a card, bug nuts.
喔 他也想让你走
Well, he wants you to leave too.
是吗 丹尼？你想让我离开？
That true, Danny? You want me to split?
- 当然了 - 嘿 传声筒…
- Of course he does. - Hey, mouthpiece…
让他回答 行吗？我必须要从大家伙那里听到
let him answer, all right? I need to hear it from the big guy.
嗯…
Well…
丹尼 告诉他你希望他走
Danny, tell him you want him to leave.
嗯 他确实帮了我们些忙
Well, he did help out a little.
帮忙？他烧了我们的沙发 现在又吃了我们所有的食物
Help? He burned our couch and now he's eating all our food.
这也叫帮忙？
You call that helping?
我懂什么？
You know what?
我还是离开这算了 我觉得自己是多余的累赘
I'm just gonna go. I feel like a third wheel anyways.
你俩这么团结
I mean, you guys are such a tight, unified team here.
啥困难都难不倒 顺便说一句 这房子可真不赖！
You're doing great too. I gotta tell you, the house looks fantastic.
那么我就闪了…
So I'll just get out of your hair…
涡刚人再来找麻烦 可别想起我喔
and let you guys whomp some more Zorgon butt without me.
等等！
Wait.
你到底是他的 还是我的弟弟？
Whose brother are you, his or mine?
你可以留下
You can stay.
既然是命令
Orders are orders.
继续游戏吧 司令 该你了
Come on, admiral, your turn.
- 对不起 - 闭嘴
- I'm sorry. - Shut up.
我觉得他能帮上忙
I think he can help.
好了 你俩怎么还不开始？
Okay. Why haven't you guys started yet?
我们等你呢
We're waiting for you.
好吧 我在这了 顺时针方向旋转钥匙…
Okay, well, I'm here, so turn that clockwise…
- 得了吧 我知道怎么玩儿 - 好吧
- Yeah, I know how to play the game. - Okay.
等一下 有点儿不对劲
Hang on a second. Something's wrong.
怎么？
What?
我本来在你前面的
I was ahead of you.
有人不小心踢到了游戏板吧？
Somebody must have kicked the board?
我看没人「不小心踢到了」
No, nobody kicked the board.
- 是你作弊了！- 我没有！
- You cheated. - No, I didn't.
你作弊！我就知道你会作弊！
You cheated. I knew you were gonna cheat.
- 这个词用得太过了！- 我没作弊！
- "Cheater's" a strong word. - I didn't cheat.
- 我就是没作弊！- 安静 安静 孩子们
- I didn't cheat! - Guys, guys. Please.
小点声 大家都冷静些！好了 你动没动棋子？
Bring it down. Indoor voices. Now, did you move the piece?
或许是我不小心动了棋子
Maybe I moved the piece by an accident.
好了 他不是故意的
Okay. It was an accident.
怎么可能会「不小心了移动棋子」？
How can you move a piece by accident?
本来那么牢固 不可能移动的 你作弊了
It's stuck to the game. It's impossible. You cheated.
不 不 不别用那个词 不 不许说「作弊」
No, no, no, let's not use that word. No, stop saying "cheated."
- 你作弊了！骗子！- 我没作弊！
- You cheated! Cheater! - I didn't cheat!
别再吵了 好不好？你动之前棋子在哪里？
Come on. Okay? Now, where did you move from?
就在这儿
I was right here.
才不是呢！你刚才是在那儿
No, you weren't. You were back there.
好吧
Okay.
好吧 小小心！
Okay. Here, careful.
- 上帝啊 - 好了 就是这儿了
- God. - Okay, it's fixed.
- 你真不懂事！- 我才不是呢！
- You're such a baby. - I'm not a baby.
行了 行了
Slow down. Slow down.
- 我不是！- 你就是！
- I'm not a baby. - You're a baby.
这里没有不懂事的小屁孩！
Nobody is a baby here.
- 我不是小屁孩！- 你就是小屁孩！
- I am not a baby! - You're a little baby!
我不是小屁孩！
I'm not a baby!
上帝啊 有完没完！行了
Jeez, it won't stop! Please.
好了 赶紧继续游戏吧！
Okay, Let's play the game.
好吧
Fine.
转个不停！？
Won't stop spinning.
- 怎么回事？- 被你弄坏了！
- What's wrong with it? - You broke it.
看 卡片出来了 看到没？它自己复原了
Oh, look, there's the card. See? It fixed itself.
「发现作弊者 自动弹射」？
"Caught cheating. Automatic ejection?"
- 说我吗？- 喔 你确实移了棋子
- Does it mean me? - Well, you did move the piece.
他才是作弊的人
He's the one who cheated.
沃尔特！
Walter!
撑住 沃尔特！
Hang on, Walter!
我来救你了
I'll save you.
救命！
Help!
等一下！我有主意了！
Wait a minute! I got an idea!
我会把这个灯扔给你…
I'm gonna swing this lamp up to you…
你一抓住它 我就可以拉你下来了
and you grab it, and I'll pull you down.
快我撑不住了！
I can't hang on any longer!
别急 我再找个灯去
Don't worry, I'll get another lamp.
退后点
Stand back.
沃尔特？
Walter?
沃尔特
Walter.
噢 不
Oh, no.
你还好吧？
You okay?
没事吧？
Are you okay?
离我远点儿
Get away from me.
对不起
Sorry.
到家之前都别跟我说话！
Don't talk to me till we get home.
你在底下看得津津有味吧？
That look cool from down here?
我俩可累得够呛… 那是相当的紧张
Because up there it was… It was pretty intense.
而我的心脏都快跳出来了 不过倒真挺有意思
My heart's pumping pretty good. That was fun.
你还不快过去接着玩儿？快过去啊 离我远点儿！
Can you just play so I can get the heck out of here and get away from you?
- 我说对不起了 - 随你便
- I told him I was sorry. - Whatever.
好了 知道我们该做些什么吗？
Okay, you know what we need to do?
我们得消除彼此的成见
We need to get our heads right, okay?
并齐心协力
Pull it together. As a team.
我们三个！
The three of us.
该你了 哥儿们 努力点儿送我们回家
You're up, big man. Bring us home.
没事儿的 我罩着你 哥儿们 说到做到
I got you, buddy. I promise.
- 写的什么？- 他不认字
- What's it say? - He can't read.
「丢失星系地图 退后两格 」
"Lose map of galaxy. Go back two spaces."
妈的 冻死我了
I'm freezing my ass off.
40度？这俩小混蛋！
Forty degrees? Those savages.
耶 9！
Yes. Nine.
- 转得好 - 转得好？
- Good roll. - Good roll?
- 应该说太棒了！- 我就是这个意思
- Nine's a great roll. - I meant great.
金色的？！
It's gold.
「流星 经过时许一个愿望」
Shooting star. Making a wish as it passes.
这定是整个游戏里最棒的卡片啦
That's gotta be the best card in the whole game.
我快走完了 看 还有几步我就赢了！
I'm almost to the end, look. A few more and I win.
我也希望你赢 事实上 我不在乎谁赢
I hope you win. I don't care who wins.
- 反正你什么都赢不了 - 嘿
- Because you never win at anything. - Hey.
怎么了？正因为那样他才作弊 他从来都没赢过！
That's why he cheats, he can never win.
- 我能赢！- 喔 你当然
- No, I don't. - Yeah, you do.
刚才你差点害死我！
And you almost got me killed.
- 那不是我的错！- 不是你的错？
- It wasn't my fault. - It's not your fault?
怎么不是你的错？那全是你的错！
How is it not your fault? This is all your fault.
你总是把事情搞砸！
Everything's your fault.
因为你 爸妈才离婚的！
It's your fault Mom and Dad got divorced.
- 嘿！- 去你的！
- Hey. - You suck.
丹尼！
Danny.
我该许愿了吧？
I get my wish now, don't I?
是啊
Yeah.
别那么做
Don't do it.
别做什么？
Don't do what?
别许这个愿
Don't wish what you're thinking.
你又不知道我在想什么
You don't know what I'm thinking.
喔 至少我敢肯定不是什么好事
Yeah, well, I can tell it ain't good.
听着 人生气的时候 是不会有什么好主意的…
Listen. No matter how good an idea seems like when you're angry…
无论那想法有多诱人 这事你得相信我 沃尔特
it never is. You gotta trust me on this one, Walter.
你许了什么愿？
What'd you wish for?
- 我不能告诉你 - 告诉我！
- I can't tell you. - Tell me.
大家都知道如果把愿望告诉别人 就…
You know the rules about wishing. If I told you, it won't…
告诉我你许了什么愿！
Tell me what you wished for.
放开我！
Get off me.
丹尼！
Danny.
愿望实现了
The card worked.
是啊 实现了祝贺你了
Yeah. It worked, congratulations.
现在我们得接受 永远被困在宇宙中的事实了
We're stuck in space now forever.
别和他吵！
Leave him alone.
你许的什么愿？
What did you wish for?
- 这个 - 你许愿要了个橄榄球？
- This. - You wished for a football?
可是布莱特·法佛尔（著名橄榄球星）签名的
Signed by Brett Favre.
为什么许这个愿？
Why'd you wish for a football?
你本可以许愿让这游戏结束的！
You could have just wished the game over.
你本可以许愿让我们离开这里的！
You could have wished us out of here.
我当时太紧张了 他冲我大喊大叫的！
I was under a lot of pressure. He was yelling at me.
你干嘛对他大喊大叫？
Why were you yelling at him?
好吧 伙计们
Okay, guys.
事情是这样的
Here's the thing.
我以前玩过这个游戏
I've played this game before.
知道吗？15年前我和我弟弟玩过这个游戏
Okay? I played it with my own brother 15 years ago.
- 你也玩过？- 是的 和你们一样
- You're a player? - Yeah. Just like you guys.
我们那时总闹不和
We were fighting a lot back then.
而开始那个游戏后 情况就变得更糟了
And when the game started, it got even worse.
每过一回合 我俩就恨对方多一点
Every time we spun, we got madder and madder at one another.
接着 我得到了许愿的机会
And then I landed on the star space.
就像刚才沃尔特那样的
The same one that Walter just landed on.
喔 我太生他的气了 所以当流星经过时…
Well, I was so mad at him, that when the star passed…
我许下了心中的愿望
I made my wish.
你许了什么愿望？
What'd you wish for?
我许愿我希望我弟弟不要出生
I wished that my brother had never been born.
噢 我的上帝啊！
Oh, my God.
马上我就后悔了
Soon as I did it, I felt horrible.
我以为 如果我有机会再转到9…
I thought, you know, if I could spin again…
也许我能再次登陆到其它星球上… 把他带回来
maybe I could land on another star space and… And wish him back.
但是 我没有办法…
But the game wouldn't let me…
因为我的回合结束了
because it wasn't my turn.
沃尔特
Walter.
有些游戏…
There are some games…
你一个人玩儿是不够的
you can't play alone.
那么 我们现在该怎么做？
So, what do we do now?
下楼去 然后一气呵成把它玩完
We go back downstairs and we finish this thing once and for all.
不许再作弊 不许再争吵
No more cheating. No more arguing.
你们要做的就是再拧几次钥匙
All you guys have to do is spin a few more times.
无论发生什么事 我都会帮助你们度过难关
I'll help you fight off whatever comes out.
说定了？
Deal?
- 说定了 - 说定了
- Deal. - Deal.
是不是变热了？
Is it getting hot in here?
你们把高炉下的标灯吹灭了吧？
You blew out the pilot light on the furnace, right?
呆在这别动
Stay put.
涡刚人又来了
Zorgons.
我的沙鼠
My gerbil was in there.
那可糟糕了
This is bad.
有大麻烦了
This is very bad.
怎么了？我们没被它们吃了
Why? We didn't get eaten.
你把游戏放哪儿了？
Where did you leave the game?
客厅啊
In the living room.
这下好了
Great.
只有游戏才能带我们回去
The game's our only way home,
而现在涡刚人把它弄去当燃料了
and now the Zorgons are burning it.
我们还有一个办法
There is one thing we can do.
还等人请你们啊？快来吧！
Waiting for an invitation? Come on.
- 弄好的放到这里来 - 来啊
- Put your back into it. - Come on.
为什么我们要这么做？
Why are we doing this?
沃尔特？
Walter?
你们要烧了房子啊？！
You guys actually set the house on fire!
- 丽莎回来了！- 丽莎解冻了！
- Lisa's back. - Lisa's unfrozen.
你没事 太好了 丽莎！
You're okay. You're okay, Lisa.
放开我！放开我！赶紧去找灭火器！
Get off me! Get off me! Try and find the fire extinguisher!
- 不 丽莎 等等 不 丽莎 等等 - 不 丽莎 不
- No, Lisa, wait. No, Lisa, wait. - No, Lisa, no.
- 停下！丽莎 别！- 火能把涡刚人招来！
- Stop! Lisa, don't. - The Zorgons are attracted to fire.
丽莎 别！
Lisa, stop.
不 丽莎！别这样！
No, Lisa, don't do it!
别 丽莎！我们得留着火！
No, Lisa, don't do that. We gotta keep the fire.
火能招来涡刚人！
The Zorgons are attracted to fire!
丽莎 等等 不 丽莎 别这样
Lisa, wait. No, Lisa, don't do it.
不 丽莎！
No, Lisa.
- 这下好了 - 现在我们再也拿不回游戏了
- Great. - Now we'll never get the game back.
好了 别担心 它们回来了
Okay. Don't worry. They're back.
- 你是谁？！- 帮忙的宇航员
- Who the hell are you? - The astronaut.
从你们玩的游戏里
From the game we're in.
丹尼招我来的
Danny spun me.
那是什么？！那是什么？！
What is that? What is that?
发生什么了？！我们在哪儿？！
What's going on? Where are we?
你们谁快说句话啊？！
Somebody please talk to me right now!
好啦 它们在装备叉子 准备登陆我们这里了
All right, they're arming the harpoons. They're gonna board us.
- 什么要登陆？！- 伙计们 机灵点儿
- What's gonna board us? - Guys, look alive.
- 什么要登陆？！- 涡刚人
- What's gonna board us? - The Zorgons.
- 涡刚人是什么？- 是蜥蜴人 它们吃肉
- What's a Zorgon? - They're lizard-men. They eat meat.
而我们是肉！
We're meat!
- 我们快躲到楼下！- 好 听着 他们过来以后…
- Come on, Iet's hide downstairs! - Okay, listen, when they dock…
我会潜入飞船 把游戏拿回来 明白了？
I'll sneak on the ship and steal the game. You got it?
- 等一下 - 怎么了？
- Hang on. - What?
- 她刚才说楼下？- 噢 不
- Did she say downstairs? - Oh, no.
嘿 嘿！
Hey, hey.
和我们呆一块儿 一切都会没事的
Just stay with us, and everything will be okay.
我不会离开你的
I'll never leave you.
快！快！快！
Move, move, move.
走！快走！
Go, go.
好了 外面情况危急
Okay. It's gotten pretty serious out there.
你们得躲在这里
I need you guys to hide in here.
用这个和我保持联络
I'll keep in touch with these.
这没法用 被丹尼弄坏了
They won't work. Danny broke them.
天线被揪下来了 彻底没救了
He pulled off the antenna. They're completely destroyed.
试音
Testing.
管用了
It works.
听好 调低音量
Listen, keep the volume low.
尽量在逼不得以时再用它
Only use that if you need me.
等… 等等 你去哪儿？
Wa… Wait, where are you going?
去找回游戏
I'm gonna go find the game.
他的眼睛好漂亮
He has gorgeous eyes.
怎么？
What?
很明显 他想保护我
He obviously feels very protective over me.
我只是…
I just…
我只是觉得在他身边很有安全感
I just feel so safe around him.
涡刚人
Zorgons.
哦 上帝！
Oh, my God.
到处都是 它们包围了整个地下室
The place is crawling with them. They're all over the basement.
等等 我好像在角落里看到游戏了
Wait, I think in the corner I see the game.
对 盒子就在那里！
Yeah, the box is right there.
先这样 我… 我得再靠近点儿
Hang on, I'm… I'm gonna get closer.
他拿到游戏了吗？
Did he get the game?
- 喂？- 怎么了？
- Hello? - What's going on?
在吗？喂？
Are you there? Hello?
- 怎么了？- 喂？
- What's happening? - Hello?
他死了吗？
Is he dead?
游戏就放在那
The game was right there.
就在壁炉对面 可我没法拿到
It was right across from the furnace. I couldn't get it.
太多涡刚人了 充满了整个地下室！
There's too many of them down there. They're all over the basement.
楼上有吗？
Are there any upstairs?
现在还没 可一旦它们收拾完楼下…
Not yet. But as soon as they're done down there…
没关系 你已经尽力了
It's okay. You tried your hardest.
- 我们相信你 - 省省吧你！
- We believe in you. - Will you please?
好吧
Okay.
- 可以用那小升降机 - 什么？
- The dumbwaiter. - What?
小升降机就停在壁炉对面
The dumbwaiter is across from the furnace.
那是个小升降梯
It's a little elevator.
你可以从那里潜入…
You could sneak right in it…
我们先把你放下去…
we'll lower you down…
接着你拿上游戏…
you could grab the game…
然后我们再把你拉上来
and we'll pull you right back up.
很简单
So easy.
是吧 沃尔特？
Right, Walter?
对啊 不过他体积似乎太大了
Yeah, but he's too big.
是啊
Yeah.
不过 这还算是个好主意
It was a good plan, though.
确实是个好主意
It was a great plan.
对啊
Yeah, it was.
的确
It was.
他进不去 真太糟了
Too bad he wouldn't fit.
连我都进不去
I wouldn't even fit.
其实只要有个个子足够小的人
I sure wish we knew someone that was small enough.
我们真那么需要那游戏吗？
Do we really need the game?
没事吧？
How you doing in there?
还好
Okay.
听我说 别紧张 好吗？
Listen to me. It's gonna be real easy, okay?
把你放下去 一拿上游戏 我们就拉你上来
Just gonna lower you down there, grab the game, and we'll pull you up.
好吧
Yeah.
你会照顾好自己的 对吧？
Nothing's gonna happen to you, okay?
- 对 - 记得我是你哥哥
- Yeah. - Because I'm your brother.
做哥哥的义务
And that's what being a brother means.
就是得尽自己所能保护你
Means I'll never let anything happen to you.
- 相信我？- 当然
- Okay? - Yeah.
那好 只要几秒钟 别紧张
Okay. This is just gonna take a few seconds, okay?
- 嘿 沃尔特 - 怎么？
- Hey, Walter? - Yeah?
很抱歉我作弊了
I'm sorry I cheated.
没关系
I know.
- 准备好了？- 好了
- You ready to do this? - I'm ready.
它就在那儿
He's right there.
你们怎么停了？
Guys, why did you stop?
快点啊
Guys, come on.
我还没到底呢
I'm not at the bottom yet.
快来帮帮我
Help me. Come on.
对 拉 拉 快点！
That's it. Pull, pull. Come on, come on.
拉 拉
Go. Go.
它们回来了 它们要上楼了！
They're back. They're coming up the stairs.
快进去 快！
Get out of here. Go on.
快！
Go, go, go.
噢 不
Oh, no.
伙计们
Guys.
那只是个空盒子
It was just the box.
等等 我看到游戏了！
Wait. I see the game.
在涡刚人的飞船上
It's on the Zorgon ship.
我想我能拿到！
But I think I can get it.
丹尼 别上那飞船！
Danny, do not get on that ship.
呆着别动 我们去找你
Just stay put. We'll come and get you.
丹尼
Danny.
丹尼 丹尼 听我说
Danny. Danny, listen to me.
涡刚人在我们这儿 你先呆着别动
The Zorgons are up here. Just stay put.
滑轮坏了… 想办法…
The pulley broke… …figure out…
我们找到绳子了… 你再等一下
We got rope… So just stay put.
丹尼 丹尼 你在那儿吗？
Danny. Danny, are you there?
丹尼 涡刚人把我们困住了
Danny, the Zorgons are up here.
听好
If you can hear me, listen.
我们现在不能拉你上来 你呆在那里先别动
We're not pulling you up right now. Stay put.
我们刚看到一个坚持住
We just saw one. Hold tight.
我只是只山羊 只是只山羊
It's just a goat. It's just a goat.
只是个…
It's just a…
我不是只山羊不是只山羊
It's not a goat. It's not a goat. It's not a goat.
我不是山羊
It's not a goat. It's not a goat.
It's not a goat.
我不是山羊
伙计们 拉我上去
Guys, pull me up.
它们养了四只眼睛的山羊！
They got goats with four eyes.
伙计们 快点！
Guys! Quick!
我拿到游戏了！
I have the game!
过来！
Come on.
沃尔特
Walter.
我说过不会让你受到任何伤害的 来！
I told you I wouldn't let anything happen to you. Come on.
紧急情况
Emergency.
发现外来生物
Alien life form.
必须消灭
Must destroy.
它还想杀我
He still wants to kill me.
用那张卡片 快！
Use the card. Quick.
程序重组
Reprogram.
发现外来生物
Alien life form.
必须消灭
Must destroy.
发现外来生物
Alien life form.
必须消灭
Must destroy.
大概那卡就这作用吧
Guess that's what the reprogram card's for.
挺好用的
I like that card.
是啊 好卡
It's a good card.
丽莎在哪？
Where's Lisa?
丽莎…
Lisa…
在楼上呢！
is upstairs.
什么声音？
What fell?
有些过分了不过我喜欢 来！
Little excessive, but I like it. Come on.
快 快 快
Come on, come on, come on.
好 快 继续
Okay, spin it, buddy.
快到了
Almost there.
拿到了！
I got it.
「惧怕宇宙学院 后退一格」
Flunk space academy. Go back 1space.
真是臭手气
I'm not even gonna comment on that.
到我了
My turn.
击中时间隧道 后退3格 重复上一回合
Hit time warp. Go back 3 spaces. Repeat last turn.
我又可以许个愿！
I get another wish.
谢谢你对我们的帮助
Thanks for helping us out.
我希望能让宇航员的弟弟获得重生
I wish the astronaut had his brother back.
你许愿要了两个我？
You wished for two of me?
不 我…
No. I…
我许愿希望 能让宇航员的弟弟获得重生
I wished the astronaut guy had his brother back.
- 丹尼 - 你是谁？
- Danny. - Who are you?
是我
It's me.
沃尔特 你哥哥
It's Walter. I'm your brother.
- 什么？- 什…
- What? - Wha…
不 你不是！
No, you're not.
他才是
He is.
对
Yes.
我是长大了但我就是沃尔特
I'm older, but I'm him.
- 我是特意回来找你的 - 这是怎么了？
- I came back for you. - What's going on here?
太帅了！
That was awesome.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我…
I…
- 我没有… - 你做的很好
- I didn't… - You did a good job.
处理得比我好多了
You did better than I did.
谢谢
Thanks.
现在 保证把他安全带回家 好吗？
Now, make sure he gets home safe, okay?
好的
Okay.
- 他就是我 - 是啊
- He was me. - Yeah.
噢 上帝 我还想…
Oh, my God. And I wanted to…
10再有10步你就赢了
Ten. You need 10 to win.
来个10 来个10！
Need a 10. Need a 10.
1？！上帝 真衰！
One. God, I suck.
你想在星球上荡秋千吗 前进9格
Would you like to swing on a star? Move ahead 9 spaces.
- 丹尼 你赢了 - 赢了？
- Danny, you won. - I won?
- 他赢了？- 你赢了 丹尼 胜利了
- He won? - You won, Danny. You beat the game.
你赢了 我们可以回家了
You won the game. We can go home.
我到达Zathura了！
I reached Zathura!
「游戏结束 谢谢」？
"Game over. Thank you for playing?"
- 就这样？- 然后呢？
- That's it? - Now what?
我觉得咱们到家了
I think we're home.
沃尔特！
Walter!
丽莎！
Lisa!
这是个黑洞！
It's a black hole!
Zathura是个黑洞！
Zathura is a black hole!
丹尼！
Danny!
不！
No!
两分全垒打！不可思议！
Two-run shot. Are you kidding me?
沃尔特？
Walter?
别按那个钮
Don't push that button.
理查德又回来啦！
Richard's back!
- 我成功了！- 你赢了！
- I did it. - You won the game.
- 我赢了！我赢了Zathura！- 我们到家了！
- I won the game. I beat Zathura. - We're home.
- 我们回家了！- 成功了！我们回家了！
- We're home! - We did it. We're home.
我好象地记得告诉你们别玩过火了！
I distinctly remember asking you guys not to kill each other.
爸 太棒了 有个游戏…
Dad, it was so awesome. There was this game…
- 它把我们送到了外太空 - 还有个黑洞
- and it sent us to outer space. - And there was a black hole.
我们差点被永远困在那儿
We almost had to stay forever.
我从涡刚人那里偷回游戏
I stole the game from the Zorgons.
而我看到未来的自己了
And I saw myself older.
听起来很有意思啊！
Sounds like a lot of fun.
快3点了 妈妈随时会到
It's almost 3:00, and Mom's gonna be here any minute.
拿上所有的书 游戏 任何你们想带到她那里的东西
Grab all games and books, whatever you wanna take to her house.
来吧 准备走了
Come on, get ready to go.
扔得好！正中胸前 接这个
Good throw. Right to the chest. Catch this one.
- 接住啦！- 漂亮
- Caught it. - Nice.
准备好了？要投了
All right, ready? Here we go.
布莱特·法佛尔准备向后投球
Brett Favre takes the snap.
他在寻找队友 传得好！
He's looking. It's a great pass.
- 触地得分 - 触地得分
- Touchdown. - Touchdown.
- 妈妈 就好！- 嘿 妈妈
- Just a second, Mom. - Hey, Mom.
布莱特·法佛尔签名的那个橄榄球哪去了？
What happened to the football signed by Brett Favre?
- 不见了 - 为什么？
- It's gone. - What happened to it?
什么都没发生过
It never happened.
噢 好吧
Oh, right.
我们永远都不再提这事 好吗？
We never speak of this. Okay?
- 没发生过！- 没发生过
- Never happened. - Never happened.
还觉得我的眼睛漂亮么？
Still think I have gorgeous eyes?
- 沃尔特 - 怎么了？
- Walter. - What?